# David **Ibáñez**





23 years old student of Engineering in Computer Science at University of Chile, and self-taught developer, is looking for an intership starting in January. Zealous about software engineering from an early age, currently interested in software development, static analysis, proof assistants and education.

#### **Education**



**Engineering in Computer Science** 

Mar 2020 - Present

Faculty of Physical and Mathematical Sciences, University of Chile

Santiago, Chile

### Professional Experience



Feb 2023 - Present

Remote work

- Design and implementation of custom made software, primarly in Java.
- FACT: Design and implementation of batched requests for high throughput in Apache Camel.
- · Levers NetChange: Optimization of Snowflake requests, analyze and transform SQL queries to minimize DB requests.

Java Apache Camel Apache Kafka Snowflake AWS Spring Gradle



#### **Supervized Project**

Ago 2024 - Dec 2024

Santiago, Chile

- Design of abstractions for including gradual typing techniques into static analyses with abstract interpretation.
- · Helping into the design, and implementation, of analyses on top of the developed abstractions.
- · Code done in Scala using the framework Sturdy
- Working under the supervision of Matías Toro and Éric Tanter.

Scala Static Analysis



**Teaching Assistant** 

Mar 2024 - Dec 2024

Santiago, Chile

• CC4101 Programming Languages: Grading evaluations.



#### **Teaching Assistant**

Jul 2022 - Dec 2022

Santiago, Chile

• CC4005 Competitive Programming: Giving lessons, grading, and designing evaluations

C/C++ GDB



#### **Full-Stack Intern** Simple Data Corp.

Summer 2019

Santiago, Chile

- · Design and implementation of new features to existing dynamic forms module.
- Technologies: PHP, Codelgniter 3, JQuery, RabbitMQ, Postman, Linux tools.

# **Projects & Associations**

Treasurer & IT Manager

2023

Student Council of the Department of Computer Science (CaDCC)

Santiago, Chile

- Managing the organization founds and public founds provided by the department.
- · Managing CaDCC's own server and its services.

#### **Archievements**

Best Application, Verifiable Randomness Hackathon by Laboratory of Applied 2024 Santiago, Chile Cryptography and Cybersecurity (CLCERT) Place 21/105, International Collegiate Programming Contest South America/South Finals 2022 Coquimbo, Chile 2021 Place 30/63, International Collegiate Programming Contest South America/South Finals Valparaíso, Chile Place 11/153, Chilean Olympiads of Informatics (OCI) Santiago, Chile

## Skills.

Languages English | Spanish

Java, Groovy, Scala | C/C++ | OCaml, F#, F\* | Python Programming

Spring | DJango | Apache Camel | Sturdy Frameworks

Miscellaneous Linux power user | Formal Language Semantics | Static Analysis | Typst | Coq | Git Personal Interests Reading | Videogames | Anime | Programming Languages

David Ibáñez Curriculum vitae